Guide to the Quentin Anderson Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Professional Career, 1935-2002
  - Subseries III.1: Columbia University, 1935-2001
    - Staff of Columbia College: English Deparment, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Student Dissent, 1968-1969 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Thanks from University Officers and Faculty, 1961-1988 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Television Series with Charles Frankel, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - University Faculty Matters, 1977-1979 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - University of South Florida, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Who's Who, 1974-1999 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Subseries III.2: Professional Involvement, 1965-2002
    Subseries 2 contains documents related to Anderson's involvement in professional activities, both within and outside of Columbia University. This includes information on conferences Anderson attended, grants he applied for, and his activity as a member of various national literary and humanities organizations. Items which record his distinction as a fellow of New York Institute for the Humanities are held in this series. Also of special interest are materials which document Anderson's role in establishing the Lionel Trilling Seminars at Columbia and his continued participation in the event.
    - Academy of Literary Studies, 1971-1981 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Applications for Grants, 1972-1974 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Association of Literary Scholars and Critics, 1994-1995 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Cassette Recordings--Everett-Edwards, Inc, 1974-1975 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Cassette Recordings--Sussex Publications Limited, 1972-1988 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Christian Gauss Award, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Christian Gauss Award, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Christian Gauss Award, 1986 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Conferences
      - American Enterprise Institute--"Commerce and Culture," 1982 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Birmingham--On Hoggart, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - English Institute--Imperial Self Discussed, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Institute of Literature and Culture, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Lydenberg Conference on Harvard and the 1930s, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Royaumont Conference on American Fiction, 1963 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Foucault and Sennett Seminar, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Institute for Advanced Study Application, 1978-1979 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Lionel Trilling Seminars
      - 1976 (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - 1977 (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - 1978 (Box 34, Folder 12)
      - 1979 (Box 34, Folder 13)
      - 1980s (Box 34, Folder 14)
      - 1990s (Box 34, Folder 15)
      - 2000s (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - About Lionel Trilling Seminars, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Announcements, 1976-2002 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities Grant, 1973-1974 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - National Humanities Center
      - Application, 1979-1980 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1980-2001 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Fellowship Information, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - New York Institute for the Humanities
      - 1980-1987 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - 1988-1989 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - 1990-1991 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - 1992-1993 (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - 1993-1994 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - 1995-1996 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - 1997-2003 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Partisan Review Transcript from "The End of Politics?," 1993 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - PEN American Center, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Book Awards, 1985-1986 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - PMLA Editorial Board, 1975-1977 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Protest Against Richler's review of Kazin's New York Jew, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Remarks at AAPOR Panel, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Humanities Fellowship Application, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Taylor-Leach Seminar, 1984-1985 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Subseries III.3: Teaching and Lecturing Abroad, 1962-1987
    During the 1960s, Anderson was awarded two Fulbright grants to act as a visiting professor in both Sussex, England and Toulouse, France. This subseries chronicles his experiences living and working in those cities, and includes correspondence between Anderson and his colleagues, teaching materials, course descriptions, lecture notes, and information about each university. It also provides information documenting his invitations to lecture on topics related to American literature and culture in other European cities and countries, while living in abroad. Items related to Anderson's time as a resident scholar in Bellagio, Italy, and his participation in a guest lecture program in Barcelona, Spain can also be found here.
    - Barcelona Lecture Series, 1985-1987 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Bellagio Resident Scholar, 1974-1978 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Fulbright Grant --University of Toulouse
      - American Fulbright Grantees, 1962-1963 (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence With the State Department and Fulbright Commision, 1962-1963 (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - Lectures for Lille and Rome, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Lectures in Rome, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Lille, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Memorabilia, 1962-1963 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - University of Toulouse
        - American History Lectures and Notes, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 6)
        - Course Descriptions and Student Lists, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 7)
        - Survey of American Literature, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Fulbright Grant--Visiting Professorship at Sussex University
      - Correspondence Concerning English Lectures, 1966-1967 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence and Memorabilia, 1966-1967 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Course on Novel, 1966-1967 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Course on Tragedy, 19667-1967 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - German Lectures, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Isle of Thorns Lecture on American and English Fiction, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Lecture on Other Strains in American Literature (19th Century), 1966-1967 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Teaching Appointment, 1966-1967 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - University Matters, 1966-1967 (Box 38, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Personal Materials, 1937-2003
  This small series offers some documentation of Anderson's personal academic history, such as transcripts and examination booklets from Columbia University and Harvard University. Materials related to the publication of Emerson and His Legacy, the festschrift celebrating Anderson's professional career, can be found here, as well as a few examples of Anderson's own musings on his personal history and academic interests. Of particular note are the folders which document Anderson's involvement in projects related to the centennial celebration of Kurt Weill, the composer. Weill was a personal friend of the Anderson family as a result of his professional relationship with Anderson's father, Maxwell Anderson, the playwright. Mrs. Thelma Anderson gathered materials related to Quentin Anderson's death in 2003 to include in this collection; those items which include condolence letters to the Anderson family and items from the memorial service held at St. Paul's Chapel on the Columbia University campus are also contained in this series.
  - Alan Anderson, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Columbia College Class of 1937 Reunions, 1976-1992 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Darmouth Class of 1935, 1974-1995 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Festschrift, 1980-1986 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Final Examinations: Columbia and Harvard, 1937-1939 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Journal
    - 1993 August-October (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - 1993-1995, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Kurt Weill Film, 2000 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - "Mary's Story of the Graveyard," 1996 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Memorial Service, 2003 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Obituaries, 2003 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Performance in Kurt Weill Centennial Celebration, 2000-2002 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Ruminations on the Individual and Money, undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Selected Condolences, 2003 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Transcripts: Columbia and Harvard, 1944 (Box 39, Folder 8)